bpowell29a@gmail.com

Brandon Powell

https://github.com/bpowell https://brandonsdevblog.me

Collaborative, team-oriented DevOps Engineer looking to go into engineering leadership. I have 10 years of experience in building and growing teams. Doing everything from hiring, creating interview processes, interviewing, and managing. I also love to mentor and coach other engineers along their career path.

EXPERIENCE

Amplitude — Senior DevOps Engineer

April 2021 - January 2023

Architected and lead migration from Jenkins to self hosted GitHub Actions

Created a pattern and managed migrating secrets from code to Vault

Sourced, interviewed, and managed the hiring of interns

Mentored and coached junior and mid-level engineers to promotions

Project Ronin — Staff DevSecOps Engineer

March 2020 - April 2021

Migrated from Jenkins to GitHub Actions and Spinnaker

Managed multiple Kubernetes clusters across clouds

Created on-call process for entire engineering organization

Trained other engineers how to use Spinnaker to deploy their code

Architected cloud migration from Azure to Oracle

Armory Inc — Software Engineer

August 2018 - March 2020

Ran multiple proof of concepts with customers

Spearheaded initial plugin framework in Spinnaker

Evangelized Spinnaker at meetups, conferences and webinars

Created Spinnaker training for customers and prospects

Started the Security Special Interest Group for Spinnaker

Oakland University — Java Developer Analyst

April 2013 - August 2018

Modernized parts of a legacy Identity Management system

SKILLS

Languages: Go, C++, C, Python, SQL, Typescript, bash, Java
Systems: Linux (RHEL, Ubuntu,

CentOS), macOS

Databases: PostgreSQL, Oracle,

Redis

Frameworks: Spring, ReactJS,

Gorilla Mux

Version Control: git, GitHub, GitLab **Other**:Spinnaker, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI, AWS, GCP, Azure, OCI, Docker, Kubernetes, ArgoCD,

SourceGraph, Vault

PRESENTATIONS

Spinnaker Summit 2019 (1 Presentation) Spinnaker Summit 2018 (1 Presentation)

Open Apereo 2017 Conference (2 Presentations)

Merit Member Conference 2015 (1 Presentation)

Open Apereo 2014 Conference (3 Presentations)

Open Apereo 2013 Conference (2 Presentations)

COMMITTEE INVOLVEMENT

Spinnaker Security SIG (2019) uPortal Steering Committee Member (2016-2018)

Macomb Community College IT Advisor Board Member (2016-current)

AWARDS

GrizzHacks Hackathon 3rd Place (https://github.com/bpowell/GrizzHacks)

Managed and mentored a team of developers

Lead the effort to upgrade custom code to Java 8 and Spring 4

Contributed code to Open Source project uPortal

Modernized front end stack with ReactJS

Created the Oakland MySAIL Android application utilized by 20,000 students

EDUCATION

Oakland University, Rochester MI — B.S. in Computer Science

PROJECTS

Brocker — https://qithub.com/bpowell/brocker

A fun little project to play around with implementing containers from scratch.

Vim Android — https://qithub.com/bpowell/vim-android

Back in the days of Eclipse ADT and Android development, things were painful. A friend and I decided to use VIM instead to do Android.

dozerlOS — https://qithub.com/bpowell/dozerlos

I've always been interested in the lower level things in computing, so I decided to write a kernel to learn "how computers work".

Oakland University 2015 AP Award CouponWallet Hackathon 1st Place (https://github.com/bpowell/couponw

MHacks IV Top 10 (https://github.com/bpowell/mhacks)

allethackaton)